<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 17:06:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ted Shifrin’s Linear algebra and Multivariable calculus</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.recomm.Shifrin-MultivariableMathematics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 17:06:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.recomm.Shifrin-MultivariableMathematics/</guid><description>This fairly rigorous by very entertaining set of lectures (where the instructor uses blackboard!) explains all the stuff encountered in Multivariable calculus one encounters during the core years of a Fundamental Sciences programme: derivatives, volumous integrals, change of coordinates, and especially does everything in a proper linear algebraic setting (which becomes very important )
Lecture videos, notes and textbook The lectures playlist Math 3500 &amp;amp; 3510: Multivariable Calculus and Linear Algebra - YouTube No of videos : 112 Average length of video : 49 minutes Total length of playlist : 3 days, 19 hours, 28 minutes, 18 seconds At 1.</description></item><item><title>Material Recommendations</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.recomm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 17:04:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.recomm/</guid><description>Material Recommendations Ted Shifrin’s Linear algebra and Multivariable calculus</description></item><item><title>BSMS Semester 1</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/IISERM-chronicles.semester-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:07:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/IISERM-chronicles.semester-1/</guid><description>MTH101 Symmetry [[MTH101]]</description></item><item><title>12021-10-31</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/journals.daily.12021-10-31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 01:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/journals.daily.12021-10-31/</guid><description> 3:20 pm - riddyrayes.github.io is online</description></item><item><title>log: December 12021</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/journals.log.12021-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:58:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/journals.log.12021-12/</guid><description>under construction
HIGHLY Productive Pre-IISER Year and a half The story starts on 18th March, 12020. The Mathematics boards exam has just been over last day. Exam scheduled on the next day (19th) is Bengali exam. At that moment, the government announced Lockdown; which made CBSE announce postponement of board exams.
Beginning of Pandemic March-June 12020 Approach to notemaking-based study of Pure geometry and other topics July-August 12020 Introduction to Action in Physics In love with Fluid Mechanics Giving IACS Entrance September 12020 Exam month JEE Main NEST IAT October-December 12021 Unsuccessful to get an institute&amp;hellip; Discovery of Productivity Tools Re-inspiration to study for IAT'21 January-March 12021 Study and Procrastination Out of Station April-June 12021 &amp;ldquo;Obsessive Study&amp;rdquo; approach and Paper Solving August-September 12021 Exams season 2 October-November 12021 Waiting period First seat allotment December 12021 Seat allotment and admission in IISER Mohali Comprehensive academic development during the period Comprehensive list of what I have learnt Mathematics Calculus (including Multivariate Calculus) Limits ~ ε-δ definition Differential calculus of Several Variables Line, surface and volume integrals Vector, scalar fields Vector calculus Physics Mechanics in all frameworks and Action principle for dynamics First Principles in Special Relativity and Electrodynamical Classical Field Theory Foundations in Quantum Mechanics Electrodynamical approach to Electromagnetic and Electronic Circuitry Fluid Mechanics Astrophysics, Engineering, Computation Things I made up along the way Framework notation for Physics frameworks a Wiki for Fundamental Sciences using Dendron and Obsidian Things I know that awaits me Mathematics thyself The enlightenment of &amp;ldquo;actual&amp;rdquo; mathematics has brought many &amp;ldquo;good at math&amp;rdquo; students to tears as I have heard LockhartsLament - A Mathematician’s Lament by Paul Lockhart The last thing they want to hear is that math is really about raw creativity and aesthetic sensitivity.</description></item><item><title>now</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/about-ray.now/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 02:22:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/about-ray.now/</guid><description> This is a /now page for Ray
Starting Semester 1 at IISER Mohali on January 3rd, 2022</description></item><item><title>12021-11-02</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/journals.daily.12021-11-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 01:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/journals.daily.12021-11-02/</guid><description>Obsidian Graph</description></item><item><title>Best Works in SoME1</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academia.mathematics.best-works-in-some1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 01:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academia.mathematics.best-works-in-some1/</guid><description>Here are the videos that I watched and liked made for the Summer of Math Exposition - 1:
The most misunderstood equation in math (associative property) - YouTube Functions, operators, and linearity: the language of abstract math - YouTube</description></item><item><title>Books</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.books/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 01:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.books/</guid><description>Books that are currently with me
Title Author Feynman Lectures on Physics Vol I, II and III Classical Theory of Fields Statistical Physics of Particles Mehran Kardar</description></item><item><title>Hierarchial Bases in Wiki</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.workstation.wiki.hierarchical-bases/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 01:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.workstation.wiki.hierarchical-bases/</guid><description>Building an ecosystem of knowledge with the philosophy from Wiki , on top of Dendron
Note: Everything mentioned is only a presently chosen custom, and is possible to change in the future, as the wiki develops.
The Subjects As it was clarified1, its best to create the wiki in its primary stage with a cascading style definition of subjects.
Let each subject reside in their own folder with a shortened name.</description></item><item><title>About Ray</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/about-ray/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 14:56:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/about-ray/</guid><description> Now Socials Instagram @riddyrayes YouTube/Ray-MS21 Twitter @riddyrayes Twitch @riddyrayes GitHub @riddyrayes LinkedIn @riddyrayes Quora @riddyrayes</description></item><item><title>Academic Curation</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 14:29:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation/</guid><description> academia and bliss
Workstation Wiki Books Material Recommendations</description></item><item><title>Wiki</title><link>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.workstation.wiki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riddyrayes.github.io/notes/academic-curation.workstation.wiki/</guid><description>A Dendron Workspace for building a &amp;ldquo;Wiki&amp;rdquo; for Hierarchical but Networked, Non-Linear Notemaking and Studying
Note: A Wiki might have different definitions in other contexts, my definition of wiki might not match with others.
building the foundations The fundamental problem is this:
Context based notes, for example, lecture notes, book notes, etc. are the first hand-down self-documentation of the topics presented.
The fundamental philosophy behind this &amp;ldquo;Wiki&amp;rdquo;:</description></item></channel></rss>